[
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "How many times has Kirk ripped his shirt in this series?",
    "Answer 1": 10,
    "Answer 2": 5,
    "Answer 3": 13,
    "Answer 4": 8,
    "Correct Answer": 13,
    "Narrative": "Considering that there were only 79 episodes, it seems like a considerable number, doesn't it?"
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Corbomite Maneuver",
    "Question": "What organization did Balok say he represented?",
    "Answer 1": "The Fesarius",
    "Answer 2": "The First Federation",
    "Answer 3": "Cosmic Syndicate",
    "Answer 4": "Celestial Union",
    "Correct Answer": "The First Federation",
    "Narrative": "In this episode, the commander of the \"Fesarius\" was found to be a child-like alien who loved\n the beverage know as \"Tranya\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Where No Man Has Gone Before",
    "Question": "In this episode, two crew were endowed with God-like powers. Which\ntwo crew?",
    "Answer 1": "Gary Mitchell and Elizabeth \nDenher",
    "Answer 2": "Sulu and Chekov",
    "Answer 3": "Kirk and Spock",
    "Answer 4": "Scotty and McCoy",
    "Correct Answer": "Gary Mitchell and Elizabeth \nDenher",
    "Narrative": "The two crew were endowed with God-like powers due to a force field that the Enterprise passed\nthrough. Mitchell became power-mad, while Dehner was able to control her response."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Naked Time",
    "Question": "Crewman Kevin Riley barricaded himself in Engineering and repatedly\nsang the song \"I'll Take You Home Again Kathleen\". Which of these\nsingers also performed this song?",
    "Answer 1": "Elvis Presley",
    "Answer 2": "Dean Martin",
    "Answer 3": "Jerry Lee Lewis",
    "Answer 4": "Tom Jones",
    "Correct Answer": "Elvis Presley",
    "Narrative": "This song was included on Elvis Presley's album \"Fool\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "City on the Edge of Forever",
    "Question": "What drug did Doctor McCoy accidentally inject himself with in\nthis episode",
    "Answer 1": "Cordrazine",
    "Answer 2": "Tri-Ox",
    "Answer 3": "Hyronalin",
    "Answer 4": "Leporazine",
    "Correct Answer": "Cordrazine",
    "Narrative": "This drug, when given in large amount s, can cause serious mental instability. In this case, it caused McCoy to go\ntemporarily insane which ultimately made him jump through the \"Guardian of Forever\" into Earth's past."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Doomsday Machine",
    "Question": "In this episode, what happened to Commodore Decker's crew?",
    "Answer 1": "They transported to the surface\n of a planet",
    "Answer 2": "They abondoned ship in\nescape pods",
    "Answer 3": "They transported to another\nship",
    "Answer 4": "They stayed onboard",
    "Correct Answer": "They transported to the surface\n of a planet",
    "Narrative": "They crew transported to the surface of the planet that Decker's ship was orbiting. Ultimately, the Doomsday\nMachine destroyed the planet, resulting in the death of Decker's entire crew."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Catspaw",
    "Question": "In this episode, two aliens took human form and had magical powers.\nWhat device gave them this ability?",
    "Answer 1": "Transmuter",
    "Answer 2": "Universal modulator",
    "Answer 3": "Dimensional alterator",
    "Answer 4": "Cosmic resonator",
    "Correct Answer": "Transmuter",
    "Narrative": "This device was used by \"Sylvia\" to transform herself into a cat, and into a woman. Sylvia and Korob were actually creatures\nthat could not survive the conditions on the planet without the Transmuter, and they ultimately died when Kirk destroyed it."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "A Piece of the Action",
    "Question": "In this episode, Kirk teaches his captors a fictional card game. What\nwas the name of this game?",
    "Answer 1": "Stellar Flush",
    "Answer 2": "Fizbin",
    "Answer 3": "Galactic Bluff",
    "Answer 4": "Cosmic Poker",
    "Correct Answer": "Fizbin",
    "Narrative": "In this ridiculous game, some of the rules are: The second card is turned up, except on Tuesdays, If the player gets 2 Jacks, they get\nanother card \"if it's dark outside\", and the best cards to get are a King and Queen, except at night, when you want a Queen and\na Jack."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Specter of the Gun",
    "Question": "In this episode, what was the name of the alien species the crew of\nthe Enterprise encountered?",
    "Answer 1": "Romulans",
    "Answer 2": "Melkotions",
    "Answer 3": "Metrons",
    "Answer 4": "Talosians",
    "Correct Answer": "Melkotions",
    "Narrative": "The \"Melkots\", as a result of the Enterprise crew ignoring a warning not to approach their planet, caused the landing party to\nparticipate in a deadly \"Shootout at the O.K. Corral\" simulation."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Miri",
    "Question": "In this episode, the crew encounters children who, when they reach\nadulthood turn into what the children call what?",
    "Answer 1": "Grups",
    "Answer 2": "Oldies",
    "Answer 3": "Ageds",
    "Answer 4": "Adulties",
    "Correct Answer": "Grups",
    "Narrative": "Obviously a warped version of \"grown-ups\". The inhabitants of an almost identical Earth planet attempted to create immortality,\nand instead killed all of the adults, but kept the children young for hundreds of years. In the end, once they did reach adulthood,\nthey also died quickly."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Shore Leave",
    "Question": "In this episode, Kirk finds someone from his Starfleet Acadamy days,\nand has a prolonged fight with him. Who is this person?",
    "Answer 1": "Finnegan",
    "Answer 2": "Gary Mitchell",
    "Answer 3": "Ben Finney",
    "Answer 4": "Carol Marcus",
    "Correct Answer": "Finnegan",
    "Narrative": "An \"upper-classman\", Finnegan tormented Kirk in his acadamy days. In this episode, Kirk gets a chance to \"get even\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Squire of Gothos",
    "Question": "In this episode, Kirk and his landing party encounter an alien\nentity who claims to have studied Earth's past. Who is this alien?",
    "Answer 1": "Vina",
    "Answer 2": "Trelane",
    "Answer 3": "Flint",
    "Answer 4": "Sargon",
    "Correct Answer": "Trelane",
    "Narrative": "Although Trelane appears to be a powerful alien, with powers that are almost magical, he is later found to be an immature\nmember of a powerful species, and treats his \"pets\" and \"toys\" poorly."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Changeling",
    "Question": "In this episode, \"Nomad\" has incorrectly idenfied Kirk as its creator.\nKirk has to destroy Nomad before it destroys the Enterprise. How does\nKirk accomplish this?",
    "Answer 1": "Confuses Nomad with logic",
    "Answer 2": "Tricks Nomad into \"beaming\"\ninto a star",
    "Answer 3": "Uploaded a virus into Nomad",
    "Answer 4": "Generated a strong\nmagnetic field into Nomad.",
    "Correct Answer": "Confuses Nomad with logic",
    "Narrative": "Because Nomad has mistakenly identified Kirk as \"The Kirk\", his creator, and Nomad values \"perfection\", Kirk is able to\ncause Nomad to destroy itself as a result of its \"imperfection\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Dr. Richard Daystrom introduced M5, a new computer on the\nEnterprise. What type of computer was this?",
    "Answer 1": "Multitronic",
    "Answer 2": "Duotronic",
    "Answer 3": "Bio-Neural",
    "Answer 4": "Positronic",
    "Correct Answer": "Multitronic",
    "Narrative": "Multitronic computers become the future of computing in Star Trek. They were a significant improvement from the\nprevious Duotronic computer systems. Of course, this doesn't occur until well after the self-preservation and destroying of\nother Starfleet vessel issues were ironed out."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "How many times does Doctor McCoy claim, \"I'm a Doctor, not a....\"?",
    "Answer 1": 5,
    "Answer 2": 10,
    "Answer 3": 20,
    "Answer 4": 11,
    "Correct Answer": 11,
    "Narrative": "11 times in 79 episodes. That's pretty significant. He has claimed not to be a bricklayer, an escalator and an engineer, \namong other things."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "What was another name for the Pon Farr, that caused Vulcans to\nmate or die?",
    "Answer 1": "Hot blood",
    "Answer 2": "Blood fever",
    "Answer 3": "Death curse",
    "Answer 4": "Mating fever",
    "Correct Answer": "Blood fever",
    "Narrative": "In Amok Time, Spock must mate or die. That sucks."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Particles",
    "Question": "What did the \"Doomsday Machine\" use to destroy planets?",
    "Answer 1": "Antiproton beam",
    "Answer 2": "Antimatter beam",
    "Answer 3": "Antineutron beam",
    "Answer 4": "Antithoron beam",
    "Correct Answer": "Antiproton beam",
    "Narrative": "Commodore Decker described the beam fired from the Doomsday Machine as antiprotons - \"Absolutely pure\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Planets",
    "Question": "In which star system is the planet Vulcan located?",
    "Answer 1": "40 Eridani",
    "Answer 2": "Tau Ceti",
    "Answer 3": "Wolf 359",
    "Answer 4": "Barnard's star",
    "Correct Answer": "40 Eridani",
    "Narrative": "This is actually a real star system, located approximately 16.5 light years from earth."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "General Orders",
    "Question": "General order 7 prohibits travel to which planet?",
    "Answer 1": "Talos IV",
    "Answer 2": "Ceti Alpha V",
    "Answer 3": "40 Eridani",
    "Answer 4": "Ceti Alpha IV",
    "Correct Answer": "Talos IV",
    "Narrative": "Due to the Talosians ability to telepathically induce hallucinations and make people believe what is not true, Starfleet\ninstituted General Order 7, prohibiting travel to that planet \"for any reason\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Who played Spock's father and also a Romulan Commander?",
    "Answer 1": "Mark Lenard",
    "Answer 2": "Morgan Woodward",
    "Answer 3": "Barbara Babcock",
    "Answer 4": "William Campbell",
    "Correct Answer": "Mark Lenard",
    "Narrative": "Although all of these actors have played multiple roles in Star Trek: The Original Series, Lenard was Spock's father and also portrayed\nthe Romulan Commander in the episode Balance of Terror."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Planets",
    "Question": "Who inhabits the planet Holberg 917G?",
    "Answer 1": "Flint",
    "Answer 2": "Harry Mudd",
    "Answer 3": "Zephram Cochrane",
    "Answer 4": "Trelane",
    "Correct Answer": "Flint",
    "Narrative": "Flint was an immortal human who claimed to also be Mozart, and a number of other significant people in Earth's history."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "What species language is problematic for the universal translator?",
    "Answer 1": "Romulan",
    "Answer 2": "Tholian",
    "Answer 3": "Metrons",
    "Answer 4": "Talosians",
    "Correct Answer": "Tholian",
    "Narrative": "The universal translator had difficulty with the Tholians language, perhaps due to their unique structure."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "What studio originally produced this series?",
    "Answer 1": "Desilu",
    "Answer 2": "20th Century Fox",
    "Answer 3": "Warner Brothers",
    "Answer 4": "Screen Gems",
    "Correct Answer": "Desilu",
    "Narrative": "Desilu was owned by Lucille Ball, along with her husband, Desi Arnez."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "Although never used, this series opening music had lyrics. Who wrote\nthese lyrics?",
    "Answer 1": "Alexander Courage",
    "Answer 2": "D.C. Fontana",
    "Answer 3": "Gene Roddenberry",
    "Answer 4": "Leonard Nimoy",
    "Correct Answer": "Gene Roddenberry",
    "Narrative": "The lyrics were never intended to be sung. Reportedly, Roddenberry only wanted them so he could pocket some profit from them\nas a co-writer credit."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "What does dilithium do in propulsion systems?",
    "Answer 1": "Stabilize and focus matter and\nantimatter",
    "Answer 2": "Provides fuel for the warp\ndrive",
    "Answer 3": "Cools the matter/antimatter\ncontainment chamber",
    "Answer 4": "Creates a warp field",
    "Correct Answer": "Stabilize and focus matter and\nantimatter",
    "Narrative": "Dilithium acts as a stabilizer for the warp engines by focusing the matter/antimatter reaction to contain the massive energy\noutput necessary for warp propulsion."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "When Wil Wheaton asked for a raise, what did the studio offer him\ninstead of a monetary raise?",
    "Answer 1": "A promotion to Lieutenant",
    "Answer 2": "More screen time",
    "Answer 3": "Creative input",
    "Answer 4": "Directorial opportunities",
    "Correct Answer": "A promotion to Lieutenant",
    "Narrative": "Wheaton allegedly told the producers  \"So what should I tell my landlord when I can't pay my rent? 'Don't worry, I just made Lieutenant'?!"
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Props",
    "Question": "After the second season, production planned to remove Geordi's VISOR\ndue to surgery to restore his natural eyesight. Why didn't this occur?",
    "Answer 1": "The actor liked the VISOR",
    "Answer 2": "Storytelling potential",
    "Answer 3": "It made him a positive role-model\nfor the disabled community",
    "Answer 4": "Fan attachment",
    "Correct Answer": "It made him a positive role-model\nfor the disabled community",
    "Narrative": "Recognizing that the character had become a positive role model for the disabled community, producers dropped the plan."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Gene Roddenberry initially refused to cast Patrick Stewart as Captain\nPicard for a number of reasons.  Who campaigned for Stewart leading\nto the acceptance of his casting?",
    "Answer 1": "Robert H. Justman",
    "Answer 2": "Jonathan Frakes",
    "Answer 3": "Brent Spiner",
    "Answer 4": "Michael Piller",
    "Correct Answer": "Robert H. Justman",
    "Narrative": "Roddenberry wanted a character who was younger, with a full head of hair."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "What was \"The Picard Maneuver\"?",
    "Answer 1": "A tactical combat maneuver",
    "Answer 2": "Pulling down his uniform tunic",
    "Answer 3": "A diplomatic strategy",
    "Answer 4": "An emergency protocol",
    "Correct Answer": "Pulling down his uniform tunic",
    "Narrative": "The original uniforms were apparently so uncomfortable that Patrick Stewart often pulled his uniform tunic down with a snap."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Aliens",
    "Question": "The Borg became the main adversary in this series. What species was\noriginally intended to fulfil this role?",
    "Answer 1": "Ferengi",
    "Answer 2": "Q",
    "Answer 3": "Breen",
    "Answer 4": "Species 8472",
    "Correct Answer": "Ferengi",
    "Narrative": "Although they ended up as more of a comic relief, the Ferengi were originally intended to be the main adversarial species in this\nseries."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "The Inner Light",
    "Question": "Which character in this episode is Patrick Stewart's real-life son?",
    "Answer 1": "Young Batai (Kamin's son)",
    "Answer 2": "Batai (Kamin's friend)",
    "Answer 3": "Administrator",
    "Answer 4": "Protector",
    "Correct Answer": "Young Batai (Kamin's son)",
    "Narrative": "Patrick Stewart's real-life son, Daniel Stewart. In the episode, he was named after Kamin's friend, Batai."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "The Big Goodbye",
    "Question": "In this episode, Picard portrays a private detective in a holodeck\nsimulation. What character does Picard play?",
    "Answer 1": "Sherlock Holmes",
    "Answer 2": "Dixon Hill",
    "Answer 3": "James Bond",
    "Answer 4": "Sam Spade",
    "Correct Answer": "Dixon Hill",
    "Narrative": "Dixon Hill embodies the quintessential characteristics of a hard-boiled detective from 1940s noir fiction. He is tough, street-smart, and \noperates in a gritty, urban setting."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "The Arsenal of Freedom",
    "Question": "What caused the demise of the people of the planet Minos in this\nepisode?",
    "Answer 1": "A natural disaster",
    "Answer 2": "Their own weapons turned\non them",
    "Answer 3": "A massive solar flare",
    "Answer 4": "Alien invasion",
    "Correct Answer": "Their own weapons turned\non them",
    "Narrative": "The Minosians created a weapon that was able to learn and adapt, which ultimately turned on their creators, destroying the entire\ncivilization as a result."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "The Royale",
    "Question": "In this episode, how does the landing party eventually end their\nentrapment?",
    "Answer 1": "They buy the casino/hotel, thus\nending the story",
    "Answer 2": "They found a way to\ndisrupt the program",
    "Answer 3": "The formed an alliance with the\ncharacters",
    "Answer 4": "They find a hidden exit",
    "Correct Answer": "They buy the casino/hotel, thus\nending the story",
    "Narrative": "In this episode, the landing party enters a simulation of a hotel/casino through a revolving door. Once inside, they were trapped\nuntil they determined that following the storyline of the book the simulation was based on would conclude the program, thus freeing them."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Reunion",
    "Question": "In this episode, what did Ambassador K'Ehleyr and Worf mainly have\nin common?",
    "Answer 1": "Their son, Alexander",
    "Answer 2": "They are both Klingon",
    "Answer 3": "They are married to each other",
    "Answer 4": "They both have strong\npersonalities",
    "Correct Answer": "Their son, Alexander",
    "Narrative": "Although they both have strong personalities and they are both Klingon, the main commonality between these two is their son, Alexander."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Deja Q",
    "Question": "In this episode, what is significant about Q?",
    "Answer 1": "He is no longer omnipotent",
    "Answer 2": "He has lost his memory",
    "Answer 3": "His appearance has been altered",
    "Answer 4": "He has become hyper\nemotional",
    "Correct Answer": "He is no longer omnipotent",
    "Narrative": "In addition to having lost his powers, Q is also completely human, including being mortal. This is particularly distressing to Q, as some\nspecies that he has tormented in the past have learned of this, and seek revenge."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Jeffrey Combs has played multiple roles in the Star Trek franchise, but\nnever appeared in this series. Which of these actors has?",
    "Answer 1": "Ethan Phillips",
    "Answer 2": "J.G. Hertzler",
    "Answer 3": "John Fleck",
    "Answer 4": "Tim Russ",
    "Correct Answer": "Tim Russ",
    "Narrative": "Tim Russ portrayed Devor in \"Starship Mine\". He also appeared on the bridge of Enterprise-B in \"Tapestry\" as a background character. Of\ncourse he is best known as Tuvok on Voyager."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Captain's Holiday",
    "Question": "In this episode, what ancient weapon were Picard and Vash looking for?",
    "Answer 1": "Tox Uthat",
    "Answer 2": "Stellum Nox",
    "Answer 3": "Pyroxin Zephyr",
    "Answer 4": "Xithar Vortex",
    "Correct Answer": "Tox Uthat",
    "Narrative": "This weapon was supposed to have the ability to halt nuclear fusion in a star. Imagine what that would do to a civilization."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Tapestry",
    "Question": "In this episode, Picard is shown to have needed an artifical heart as a\nresult of being impaled by an alien during a game of Dom-Jot? What\nalien species did this?",
    "Answer 1": "Klingon",
    "Answer 2": "Nausicaan",
    "Answer 3": "Tamarian",
    "Answer 4": "Antican",
    "Correct Answer": "Nausicaan",
    "Narrative": "Picard and his friends discovered that the Nausicaans had rigged the table to cheat. Picard, known for his bold and sometimes brash nature\n in his youth, confronted the Nausicaans and got into a fight with them."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Devil's Due",
    "Question": "In this episode, what species is mentioned to have influenced the \nVentaxians?",
    "Answer 1": "Klingons",
    "Answer 2": "Romulans",
    "Answer 3": "Vulcans",
    "Answer 4": "Andorians",
    "Correct Answer": "Klingons",
    "Narrative": "There is a great deal of Klingon influence in this story. It is mentioned that first contact with Ventax II was made by the Klingons 70 years\n previously. Data mentions a legal case involving a Klingon, and Ardra uses a Klingon image to intimidate the Ventaxians."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "The Host",
    "Question": "What species, to later appear in Deep Space Nine, was the symbiot\nin this episode?",
    "Answer 1": "Trill",
    "Answer 2": "Organian",
    "Answer 3": "Angosian",
    "Answer 4": "Tamarian",
    "Correct Answer": "Trill",
    "Narrative": "The Trill species will return in the characters of Ezri and Jadzia Dax and others in later series."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "In which episode of this series did Thomas Riker first appear?",
    "Answer 1": "The Best of Both Worlds, Part I",
    "Answer 2": "The Inner Light",
    "Answer 3": "Second Chances",
    "Answer 4": "The Outcast",
    "Correct Answer": "Second Chances",
    "Narrative": "Thomas Riker, created as a duplicate of William Riker as a result of a transporter accident first appeared in this episode."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "In the episode \"New Ground\", what method of propulsion was \nintroduced?",
    "Answer 1": "Soliton wave",
    "Answer 2": "Quantum torpedo",
    "Answer 3": "Transwarp conduit",
    "Answer 4": "Dyson sphere",
    "Correct Answer": "Soliton wave",
    "Narrative": "The soliton wave generator on a planet would create a powerful, stable wave in subspace. This wave would then be used to propel a starship at \nfaster-than-light speeds without the need for a warp drive on the ship itself. Ultimately, it failed."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "A Fistful of Datas",
    "Question": "In this episode, Worf and Alexander play what role in the simulation?",
    "Answer 1": "Lawmen",
    "Answer 2": "Cowboys",
    "Answer 3": "Outlaws",
    "Answer 4": "Bartenders",
    "Correct Answer": "Lawmen",
    "Narrative": "Alexander, being a fan of Westerns, eagerly immerses himself in the role of the sheriff's deputy, while Worf reluctantly takes on the role\n of the sheriff."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "In the episode \"Relics\", what TOS character was featured?",
    "Answer 1": "Scotty",
    "Answer 2": "Chekov",
    "Answer 3": "Doctor McCoy",
    "Answer 4": "Spock",
    "Correct Answer": "Scotty",
    "Narrative": "The Enterprise stumbles upon a Dyson sphere, with a ship crashed on the outer surface. An away team finds some systems still powered up\n and the chief engineer from the old Enterprise, Montgomery Scott, locked in the transporter cycle."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "A Fistful of Datas",
    "Question": "In this episode, what primary role does Data play in the simulation?",
    "Answer 1": "Frank Hollander",
    "Answer 2": "Hank Frolander",
    "Answer 3": "John Carpenter",
    "Answer 4": "Mark Target",
    "Correct Answer": "Frank Hollander",
    "Narrative": "Data appears in the simulation in multiple rolls, including a prisoner named Eli Hollander, who is Frank's son. Funny note, as the simulation\nprogresses, Data himself starts speaking with a southern drawl."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Chain of Command, Parts I and II",
    "Question": "In this episode, Picard is captured by the Cardassians and is tortured by\nhis interrogator, Gul Madred. Madred asks Picard how many lights he\nsees. What is Picard's reply.",
    "Answer 1": "There are four lights",
    "Answer 2": "There are five lights",
    "Answer 3": "There are two lights",
    "Answer 4": "There are twenty lights",
    "Correct Answer": "There are four lights",
    "Narrative": "There are actually four lights, but Madred insists there are five, and wants Picard to break by answering that there are five lights. Picard never\ngives in, no matter how long this torture persists."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Unlike Kirk in TOS, Picard is not often thought of as a \"ladies man\". But\nhe did have several love interests over the course of the series. Of the\nfollowing pairs, which were love interests of Picard?",
    "Answer 1": "Vash and Daren",
    "Answer 2": "Keiko O'Brien and Dr. Ogawa",
    "Answer 3": "Dr. Leah Brahms and  Commander\nShelby",
    "Answer 4": "Ro Laren and Guinan",
    "Correct Answer": "Vash and Daren",
    "Narrative": "Vash and Daren were both love interests of Captain Picard over the course of the series. Although Daren only appeared in a single episode,\nVash made several appearances."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Inheritance",
    "Question": "In this episode, Data discovers his \"Mother\" on the planet Atrea IV. What\nwas her name?",
    "Answer 1": "Dr. Juliana Tainer",
    "Answer 2": "Dr. Leah Brahms",
    "Answer 3": "Dr. Beverly Crusher",
    "Answer 4": "Dr. Kahn Noonien Soong",
    "Correct Answer": "Dr. Juliana Tainer",
    "Narrative": "It turns out that Dr. Tainer is also an android, but believes she is human. She was constructed by Dr. Noonien Soong, who was also responsible\n for creating Data and Lore. She was constructed to believe she was human and was given the memories and personality of Soong's real \nwife, Juliana O'Donnell."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Masks",
    "Question": "How many characters did Brent Spiner portray in this episode?",
    "Answer 1": "Five",
    "Answer 2": "Four",
    "Answer 3": "Three",
    "Answer 4": "Six",
    "Correct Answer": "Five",
    "Narrative": "Spiner portrayed five characters in all, including Data. Investigating a rogue comet that's been traveling throughout the universe for over\n 87 million years, Picard discovers alien beings within the comet, which infest the computer systems on the Enterprise, as well as Data."
  }
]